ELLA QIONGYU MENG

(313) 585-0425 giongyu@umich.edu 2801 Towner Blvd. Ann Arbor, MI 48104

SUMMARY:

Master of Health Informatics student with three years of experience in Quality Management seeking 2016 summer internship to combine interest of problem solving, data analytics and health informatics technology for the purpose of improving healthcare quality.

EDUCATION:

UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN
School of Public Health & School of Information
Master of Health Informatics GPA: 3.8/4.0

Ann Arbor, MI April 2017

SHENYANG PHARMACEUTICAL UNIVERSITY

School of Pharmacy

China June 2012

Bachelor of Science in Pharmacy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Shanghai Hengrui Pharmaceutical Co., LTD

China

QA Specialist (Quality Management Department)

Aug. 2014-July 2015

- Point of contact to external partner handling international expansion initiative: convened weekly meetings with other departments, and tracked progress of expansion process.
- Managed pre-audit and audit process between organization and foreign affairs, including FDA inspection, to guarantee the successful pass of the inspection.
- Collaborated with external departments to ensure worker adherence to Good Manufacturing Practice (GMP), including Change Control and Non-Conforming Materials.

Shanghai Hengrui Pharmaceutical Co., LTD

China

IC (In-process Control) Specialist (Quality Management Department)

July 2012-July 2014

- Supervised production process, including monitoring the personnel operation and environment, to guarantee the products quality.
- Analyzed data from personnel and environmental monitoring to support monitoring standards.

SELECT PROJECTS:

Ann Arbor MI

Smart Pills

Jan. 2016-Present

• Developing Bluetooth enabled iOS medicine pill reminder system to help brain injured patients improve medication adherence by using background research, comparative analysis, patients' interviews, and Lo/Hi-Fi prototypes design and test.

Ann Arbor MI

Optimize Response Workflow in UM Health System

Jan. 2016-Present

• Using the Contextual Inquiry and Project Management method to interview, analyze, and redesign UM Health System Service Desk's workflow to reduce call abandonment rate, improve first touch resolution as well as customer satisfaction.

Detroit MI

Data Mining & Mapping in Urban Neighborhood Community Development Corporation Feb. 2016-Present

Mined and formatted population, education, housing, and vacant lot data by eight sampled zip codes in Detroit
into Excel Spreadsheets, and creating an interactive ArcGIS Online map to identify causalities and to offer
better plan of prevention to build healthier and safer communities.

RELEVANT COURSEWORK:

• Statistics, Decision Support with Spreadsheets, Python, Empirical Evaluation Methods (current), Design of Complex Websites (current), Survey of the US Healthcare System (current)

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

• Python, MySQL, HTML, CSS, SPSS, MS Excel, ArcGIS, GAE